                                                                                AUGSBURG
Special Education: Academic Behavioral Strategist (B.A.)                           UNIVERSITY
2018-2019 catalog

  Student Name:                                             ID Number:

Major Requirements
All classes must be completed with a C grade or better.
Term Completed/Planned Grade  Credit  Course #Title
                                3     EDC200  Orientation to Education in an Urban Setting
                                2     EDC220  Educational Technology
                                3     EDC310  Learning and Development in an Educational Setting
                                1     EDC330  Building the Public Good: Public Achievement and Organizing I
                                1     EDC331  Practicum in Public Achievement I
                                1     EDC332  Building the Public Good: Public Achievement and Organizing II
                                1     EDC333  Practicum in Public Achievement II
                                3     EDC410  Learners with Special Needs
                                3     EED225  Foundations of Literacy
                                3     EED325  K-6 Methods: Literacy
                                1     EED326  Elementary Reading K-6 Field Experience
                                2     EED336  Advanced Literacy Methods
                                3     EED350  K-6 Methods: Mathematics
                                3     EED360  K-6 Methods: Science
                                3     SPE410  Implementing Assessment Strategies
                                3     SPE411  Etiology and Theory of Mild to Moderate Disabilities
                                3     SPE415  Theory to Practice
                                3     SPE425  Transition and Community
                                3     SPE430  Instructional and Behavioral Practices
                                3     SPE490  Parent and Professional Planning (KC)
Complete either EDC206 or both EDC210 and EDC211 (first year students may take EDC110 instead of EDC210)
                                3     EDC206  Diversity/Minnesota American Indians
                                4     EDC210: Diversity in the School and EDC211: Minnesota American Indians
Complete student teaching (SPE481, 483, 485, or 487). The number of teaching credits required will depend on a student's licensure program
                                8     EDC481  Student Teaching: Initial License (12-14 weeks)
                                2     SPE489  Teacher Performance Assessment and Student Teaching Seminar
Supporting Courses
                                4     ENL111  Effective Writing
                                2     HPE115  Chemical Dependency Education
                                4     MAT137  Mathematics for Elementary Teachers I (NSM)


Abbreviation Key: ML = Modern Language; SC = Signature Curriculum; EM = Engaging Minneapolis; AE = Augsburg Experience; KC = Senior Keystone Course; NSM = 
Natural Science & Mathematics - no lab; NSM-L = Natural Science & Mathematics-with lab; SBS = Social & Behavioral Science; FA = Fine Arts; HUM = Humanities


Student's Signature                                                                   Date



Advisor's Printed Name                        Signature                               Date

  Advisor(s): By signing, you indicate you have verified the accuracy of the information above. Faculty advisors must initial next to 
                              each course substitution/waiver and sign this form.

